<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-01-14T00:40:02+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Surreal numbers omnific integers</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2024/surrealnumbers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surreal numbers omnific integers" /><published>2024-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2024/surrealnumbers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2024/surrealnumbers/"><![CDATA[<p>I had the pleasure of spending a couple weeks learning the basics of the surreal numbers sytem, from the Peano axioms to the basic construction of surreals. At the end of this short exploration, I looked into the world of omnific integers, which generalise the concept of integers to the surreal numbers. For instance, while the integers may contain numbers such as 5, 10, or 1000, the omnific integers include numbers such as \(\omega\), which is the supposed smallest infinite number. Omnific integers allow you to do arithmetic with infinitely large numbers, and for this reason it can be extended to consider many problems in number theory as well. One aspect that I investigated very shallowly was Pell’s equation and how its solution may differ if all integers are instead omnific. 
<br />
<br />
During this short exploration, I made use of Knuth’s <i> Surreal Numbers <i>, which is a sort of novelette that explores the construction and discovery of surreal numbers through the lens of two individuals on a desolate island. It’s perhaps not the most rigorous “math text”, but it certainly has value and can be read like a storybook. I also looked into Conway’s (RIP) <i> On Numbers and Games <i>, which studies surreal numbers in its numerous aspects, from algebra to analysis to number theory, and eventually to the reason for its initial creation: games. It certainly is a rigorous text, but it is very self-contained, and if I had more time I would have been able to explore its nuances in much more detail than I have. At the end of my exploration, I gave a very brief presentation on omnific integers, and here are the <a href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/projectpdf/omnific_slides.pdf">slides</a>.</i></i></i></i></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fun exploration into game theory and a new number system]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cubic and Biquadratic reciprocity</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/cubicbiquadratic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cubic and Biquadratic reciprocity" /><published>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/cubicbiquadratic</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/cubicbiquadratic/"><![CDATA[<p>New project time whilst I’m on winter break! This time I’m investigating cubic and biquadratic reciprocity, and already, as I’m about 2 weeks in, there’s so much modern algebra and stuff about finite fields that I have to either relearn or refresh my memory on. So far the most important part is understanding finite fields, both in terms of construction and existence. I’m nearly done learning about the basics of finite fields, so I then have to move on to understanding multiplicative characters (I have worked with quadratic multiplicative characters in my quadratic reciprocity project, but higher reciprocity demands cubic, biquadratic, \(n\)th degree multiplicative characters), as well as the stuff that comes with it such as Gauss sums. Then I can finally approach cubic and biquadratic reciprocity. 
<br />
<br />
Maybe I’ll write a short expository paper about the journey to cubic and biquadratic reciprocity; we’ll see if I have time (If I do, I estimate that it will be perhaps 15-25 pages? I’m not quite sure yet, but it will be one of my larger projects, as it also hinges upon parts of my quadratic reciprocity project). This is kind of my last expository venture as from now on pretty much everything is going to be different, and original research will finally (kind of) be in my grasp!
<br />
<br />
Anyway, I will update this page when I either produce or don’t produce something. I am keeping detailed notes with insights and proofs from other areas (cough cough mostly algebra), so if I don’t end up writing an expository paper I suppose I can just provide those. 
<br />
<br />
(Updated 24 December, 2023)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A new project]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journeys III</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journeys III" /><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys3/"><![CDATA[<p>In any subject, you always have feelings of self-doubt and often-times, you’re unable to consolidate feelings of giving up and dismiss them without any clear solution. Giving up is just not an option when you have come so far, and really that is reflected in the pain that is felt when one endures so much self-driven disrespect and harshness. It’s hard to come to terms with one’s own belief of excellence, and everyone suffers from this fact. This leads me to a point. I am not brilliant at mathematics. In a world of so many people, it is impossible for someone to not know more proofs than me, be better at formulating ideas, be better at writing formally, solve problems more efficiently, and so on. The list is practically infinite. 
<br />
<br />
I think that being aware of this fact is a good thing. Self-pity is often the downfall of many people, so I choose not to fall down that rabbit-hole. Maybe it doesn’t matter; maybe the point of doing mathematics is not to be the best, but to be the bravest: everyone is capable of being brave, right? Everyone is capable of being brave. Everyone, is capable of being brave. And even then, maybe it’s not about being the something-est in any realm? Maybe just go with the flow, as they say, or be human and take the praise and ridicule, then forget about it tomorrow. Maybe it’s just the small things. Look at the big picture, they say; but don’t go fighting windmills when the time isn’t right: that will just make you fight more windmills. The small things accumulate and then eventually you’ll be able to fight an army of windmills, just maybe they’re smaller. Maybe you could conquer France too (or offshore wind farms). The point is, maybe you just have to step back and think about everything for a moment. Do everything slowly, like a sloth. Eventually you will - I will - understand. It just takes some time. Sometimes that time is a lifetime, and we have to take solemn comfort in that. Imagine if you lived for eternity. Bleh.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I am not brilliant at mathematics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journeys II</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journeys II" /><published>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys2/"><![CDATA[<p>The first variant of this rather fragile topic touched upon several existential topics, so in this post we will explore several topics that are moire conventional, and are perhaps slightly easier to talk about. This of course, being, first, the idea of mathematical maturity. 
<br />
<br />
Now, there are hundreds of accounts defining the meaning of mathematical maturity, and I highly recommend simply searching for them: the answers you will find there are more meaningful than whatever I can produce here, as I myself am still in the early stages of achieving mathematical maturity. In fact, I would argue that “achieving mathematical maturity” as a goal is not truly possible. While there may be a threshold for which one’s mind becomes slightly less competent (studies have shown that there likely is no correlation between an increase in age and scientific productivity/ingenuity: see <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2778031">Age and Scientific Performance, Stephen Cole 1979</a> or <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2778031">Age and Achievement in Mathematics: A Case-Study in the Sociology of Science, Nancy Stern 1978</a>), an academic (should) never stop evolving and learning, meaning that the state of maturity is a constantly shifting constant. Mathematics in particular, as a field that is really just entirely unpredictable, demands constant flexibility from the doers of, and there’s just no time to grow old if one hopes to experience it to its fullest. So now, to speak of mathematical maturity on an elementary level, it is fair to say that this can really only first be considered upon entering university for the vast majority of future mathematicians. There are a considerable few who have already known of both their abilities and interest prior to this milestone: for instance, I had the pleasure of attending a summer class at the <a href="https://eulercircle.com/">Euler Circle</a>; this program teaches students a variety of advanced undergraduate and even some graduate topics in mathematics. Even though I produced something of decent value nat the end of this summer experience, the mathematical maturity of my peers far exceeded my own, and it was clear that they were just on a different level. I was just inspired by the competence and passion those people had for mathematics. Several of the participants in the Euler Circle had also participated in and (I believe) one had won the Regeneron Science Talent Search a few years prior. This is nothing short of extraordinary, especially when you consider how rare pure mathematics is in the general scientific community. When I think of mathematical maturity, I think about these people. It’s the ability and confidence to pick up a textbook and understand its contents without much consideration for prerequisites. I believe that mathematical maturity is the ability for one to confront new mathematical knowledge with an open and qualified mind. As I said earlier, this is impossible to achieve, as built into its very definition is the notion of “new mathematical knowledge”: nothing is really learnable in the first attempt, and there’s always bound to be something so creative and unique that even the weird geniuses will struggle to understand it. I mean isn’t that how new areas were invented - weird geniuses who stumbled upon something extraordinary? 
<br />
<br />
Now let’s talk about taking a break. Is it okay to take a break? As with most things, taking a break allows us to stand back and look at the bigger picture and appreciate life when it becomes too chaotic. Yet, I am at a point where it feels unproductive to not constantly be thinking about mathematics. Many have told me that taking a breka is not a good idea, as it reduced my capacity to learn more, but I somewhat disagree. While a break takes away valuable time to learn mathematics, it is also an opportunity to expand my range of view. While the most dedicated (complete respect to them) are hammering away at hard problems regularly, I can sit back and expand the bigger picture, allowing myself to 1) not experience burnout too soon and 2) think about what areas need improvement and most importantly 3) think about what I want to learn and what I need to do to learn it. Burnout is a severe issue in teenagers and even in academics: how dreadful would it be to fall out of love with the area you love most? Taking a break is a good way to step back and do other things: then you can return refreshed and ready to explore new areas or do new work. As for improvement, while this is still considered “thinking about math”, I find it almost therapeutic to envision what areas you are weakest in, and determine exactly what must be done to achieve your objectives. More often than not your limitations are just your weakpoints, and you can confront them directly after your break. Finally, in concert with the second point, learning new stuff is just spectacular, especially when it’s a new area that you hadn’t explored much (combinatorics for me <i> cough cough </i>). But, diving straight in is what causes burnout, so I’m stepping back to repeat the second point and wait until I have more opportuntities to really do significant work. This allows me to maintain a healthy relationship with mathematics and my learning.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What should define mathematical maturity and when it is viable to take a break?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">q-analogues</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/q-analogues/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="q-analogues" /><published>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/q-analogues</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/q-analogues/"><![CDATA[<p>While looking around for new mathematics to learn, I encountered the notion of the \(q\)-analogue. The \(q\)-analogue of some statement or concept is a parameterization of that statement in terms of some new parameter \(q\), which, when equal to \(1\), yields the original statement. If when \(q=1\) the statement is undefined or the statement involves some discontinuities, then we can determine the \(q\)-analogue when \(q\) approaches \(1\) from either the left or right. Since this is a very new concept to me, I’m just going to cover the absolute basics with the introduction of notions such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inversion_(discrete_mathematics)">inversions</a> in terms of the so-called “\(q\)-factorial”, the \(q\)-analogue of the derivative (as a brief introduction to \(q\)-calculus), and the \(q\)-analogue of the binomial theorem. We may also introduce the concept of a hypergeometric series, and will be using the Pochhammer notation for factorials. 
<br />
<br />
<i> Abstract </i>
<br />
<br />
In this expository paper, we will outline several interesting properties of the \(q\)-factorial and its relationship with inversions, the \(q\)-derivative and the \(q\)-analogue of Taylor’s theorem, a theorem about the uniqueness of \(q\)-antiderivatives up to a constant alongside evaluation of definite \(q\)-integrals, as well as several perspectives and proofs of the \(q\)-binomial theorem. We will conclude with an introduction to the \(q\)-Pochhammer symbol, and use it to define the \(q\)-hypergeometric function and prove an interesting fact about the special \(q\)-hypergeometric series \({}_{1}\Phi_{0}\). 
<br />
<br />
As of now, this paper is complete and can be found <a href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/papers/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some brief notions of q-analogues for later interest and a paper]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journeys I</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journeys I" /><published>2023-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/journeys1/"><![CDATA[<p>I am definitely not a mathematician yet, but I find the act and philosophy of doing mathematics and being mathematics to be utterly fascinating. What does it mean to be a mathematician? In his essay <i> A Mathematician’s Apology </i>, G.H. Hardy recounted his journey as a mathematician, and how he felt that he was becoming increasingly disconnected from the world around him, and how he wished that he could have been more present. I will not outline it here, but I highly encourage whoever is reading this to read its contents. (a pdf copy of this illuminating read can be found <a href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/assets/pdf/A Mathematician's Apology - G.H. Hardy.pdf"> here </a>)
<br />
<br />
What does it mean? When thinking about career choices as a person interested in pure mathematics, there’s always a dilemma. Do you pursue pure mathematics research or do you pursue industry work? While the latter earns larger sums of money, and it leads to greater opportunities to collaborate with others, pure research also occupies a vastly different position - in a more secluded, independent, and some might say “isolated” way. Now when one chooses between the two, one might also consider the amount of happiness derived from each choice of work. Communication with others is naturally viewed as something from which to derive happiness, and I completely and wholeheartedly agree; so, to pursue mathematics alone… somewhere in a dark room… lost… surrounded by one’s thoughts, must feel… lonely? I have never known this feeling. Why does one choose to pursue mathematics? I can never hope to answer this question, because it will never be answered. 
<br />
<br />
What does it mean to pursue mathematics? I’m not talking about the literal sense, or even the philosophical sense, but moreso the human sense. A human life is what - at most 90 years? There is just not enough time. One can be productive for every second of their short life in a realm of grains of time and still yet never understand the what they are doing. Until it’s too late. The brilliance is immaculate, but it’s simply so fleeting. It’s frightening, I might add - many take their own lives in fear of what they might accomplish; or what they might not accomplish. So to do mathematics, to dedicate one’s life to a study of pure human thought and something so rare and pure and treasurable, is something so bold that even the boldest could never understand. Why, when there is a world of ways to pass time in other more pleasurable ways, do people still do mathematics? When I think about this question, the only thing I can think about is how inherently human it truly is to do something of such make-believe. It really is insanity, but I guess it has been embedded in the few thousand years of human history. It’s pathetic how we have thrived with such little time. 
<br /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What does it mean to pursue mathematics?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Möbius related things (incomplete)</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/mobius/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Möbius related things (incomplete)" /><published>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/mobius</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/mobius/"><![CDATA[<p>One concept that I have been incredibly interested in but haven’t been able to properly understand or apply is Möbius inversion. So, today, we will develop the notion of it in a series of notes with comprehensive descriptions. 
<br />
<br />
To begin, let’s define what a multiplicative function, otherwise known as number-theoretic function, is. A number-theoretic function is a function that satisfies the property \(f(mn) = f(m)f(n)\) for \(\text{gcd}(m,n)=1\), or \(m,n\) coprime. If this property holds for all such \(m\) and \(n\), then the function is completely multiplicative. We now introduce the Möbius function \(\mu(n)\). 
<br /></p>

\[\begin{equation*}
\mu(n) = \left\{
\begin{array}{lr}
1 &amp; \text{if} \ n=1 \\
0 &amp; \text{if} \ p^{2}|n, \ p \ \text{prime} \\ 
(-1)^{l} &amp; \text{if} \ n=p_{1}p_{2}\cdots p_{l}, \text{where} \ p_{i}\text{s are distinct}. 
\end{array}\right}
\end{equation*}\]

<p><br />
The second property that \(\mu(n)=0\) if \(p^{2}|n\) can be restated as \(\mu(n)=0\) is \(n\) is not prime square-free, or it is divisible by the square of some prime. When we talk about number-theoretic functions, we will be using a funky looking sum. This sum is written as
<br /></p>

\[\sum_{d|n}f(d).\]

<p><br />
Essentially, it takes the sum of the function \(f(d)\) for \(d\) that divides some pre-defined number \(n\). For example, If \(f(d)=d\) and \(n\) is prime, then the only divisors of a prime number are \(1\) and itself, so that \(\sum_{d|n}f(d) = n + 1\). We now proceed to prove some important properties of multiplicative functions that will be useful when we confront Möbius Inversion. 
<br />
<br />
<b> Lemma </b>
<br />
<br />
Let \(f(n)\) be a multiplicative function, and define a function 
<br /></p>

\[F(n) = \sum_{d|n}f(d).\]

<p><br />
Then \(F(n)\) is also a multiplicative function.
<br />
<br />
<i> Proof. </i> Let there exist \(m\) and \(n\) such that \(\text{gcd}(m,n)=1\). Also, introduce two numbers \(r\) and \(s\). Then we can evaluate
<br /></p>

\[\begin{align*}
F(mn) &amp;
= \sum_{d|mn}f(d) \\ &amp; 
= \sum_{r|m, s|m}f(rs) \\ &amp;
= \sum_{r|m, s|m}f(r)f(s) \\ &amp;
= \sum_{r|m}f(r)\sum_{s|m}f(s) \\ &amp;
= F(m)F(n),
\end{align*}\]

<p><br />
which is the definition of multiplicativity for \(F\). This third row follows because the fact that \(r|m\) and \(s|n\) implies that \(\text{gcd}(r,s)=1\). This is not difficult to show. 
<br />
■</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Möbius inversion is very cool]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on research and the state of research</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/thoughts-on-research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on research and the state of research" /><published>2023-06-05T03:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-05T03:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/thoughts-on-research</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/thoughts-on-research/"><![CDATA[<p>Research, ah, research. Research has always been the medium of progress and innovation in human civilization. From the most primitive forms of discovery, to the most complex and groundbreaking forms of advancement, research has always taken multiple forms, be it in a playful and casual sense: twiddling one’s thumbs and airily thinking, or in a deliberate and serious sense: reading books, websites, and computing without distraction. Regardless, all of these forms of thinking and “work” are research. Yet, it seems that research, in the current world, has taken a familiar yet unprecedented turn; whereas before the leap to providing education we had been closed-minded and unaccepting of new progress from people of diverse backgrounds, we now take a similar leap in the alternate direction: becoming closed-minded to the meaning of research, and the meaning of making progress in different fields in such a fast-moving and elitist field of study. 
<br />
<br />
Today we will be talking largely about mathematics research, especially high school mathematics research. When I first began learning advanced mathematics beyond the conventional elementary work, I did not really consider the idea of research, and was not equipped with the tools necessary to even confront the concept of “making progress”. In the field of mathematics, “progress” is defined very differently from other fields. Rather than simply writing a paper or publishing a book on some lesser-studied topic, the complexity and crudeness of mathematics research converges on one thing: deriving some fundamentally unique and original idea, and from that idea, constructing a web of ideas to work back toward our current arsenal of mathematical ideas. Though this seems easy in word-form, it is far from that. With the enormous breadth of knowledge already dominating the current realm of mathematics, it’s almost impossible to even touch the surface of all current fields and understand everything in utmost detail. Conceptually, yes, but technically, not at all. The amount of time investment required to even begin conducting significant research in any field is enormous; to even begin is a culmination of over 10 years of decent schooling, from high school to undergraduate to graduate and then to pursuing a PhD. This truly illustrates how much human knowledge has truly progressed, and how amazing it is that several thousand of the brightest minds are able to pursue something so representative and so pure of the homo sapien sapien species. 
<br />
<br />
Yet, as competition becomes increasingly fierce, with some of the most competitive schools such as the India Institute of Technology, Tsinghua University (清华), Oxford University, the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, or countless more becoming even more and more elite, the idea of conducting any form of research prior to university has become more a matter of “proving oneself to college admissions”, or to demonstrate some degree of interest in a field, and has placed itself on a pedestal representing the “ultimate objective” of a highschool student to appear dedicated to universities. This is nonsense. Before we continue, let us define two different types of highschool research. The first variety of research is transparent; this type of research consists of work that is either interdisciplinary or focuses largely on applications or experiments. This area of research tends to be somewhat easier, and unique and original problems are not difficult to come by. We will call this Type I research. The second variety of research is research that is incredibly gruelling, and relies more on theory and rigour than practice; this type of research consists of rigorous work on theory as opposed to applications, and problems in this area are extremely difficult to come by. We will call this Type II research. The majority of highschool students who have the opportunity to conduct research choose - or perhaps are required to - to conduct Type I research. Many papers on lab experiments, biological analyses, and some form of chemical description are published each year. Type II research, alternatively, only produces a mere few papers. Why may this be? When I first faced Type II research, many things were new to me. I was entranced by the idea of publishing something significant in a journal, and was looking forward to achieving something spectacular. I had been told repeatedly and had seen on social media how people had conducted research in many different disciplines, and it seemed to me that research, especially original research, was a requirement for being accepted to a good university, and was something to “check off” on the long list of objectives in applying to university and living an optimal pre-college life. This mindset is what produces poor quality and ugly research. While I observed many of these research projects, I noticed something in common: they were all Type I research. Rarely, if at all, did I see Type II research: perhaps something in rigorous mathematics, or perhaps something in physics that did not involve some crude application? Not at all. This surprised me a great deal. While I was certain that these projects were great research projects, something bothered me, and I couldn’t pinpoint it exactly.
<br />
<br />
When prestigious universities review applications from highschool students, they search for well-rounded, well-composed, and curious students. The last criteria, “curious”, is where research falls. This implies that regardless of whether a student conducts Type I or Type II research, universities will almost always place these students in the same categories. This does not consider the difference in time and effort spent between a student conducting Type I and Type II research. The culture surrounding Type II research differs drastically from that of Type I research. In a way, Type I research is far more accessible to a general audience in that it is both visualisable and relatable. One instance of how Type I research and Type II research differ in modern culture is through cinema: Type I research is depicted as a remarkable thing with many moving parts and science-fiction-esque concepts, whereas Type II research is a jumble of unrelated ideas - and even if the film is good, it often misses the real rigour. There are two reasons for this: the audience does not care about rigour, and the director or screenwriter does not know what to portray; these people know that what they are depicting is exceptional, yet they do not have the necessary tools to convey its significance. When we speak about universities, appeal falls more on relatable and understandable things than on rigorous work. There is not much I can say about this except that it is a failure of scientific - specifically mathematical - communication. The reason that many beautiful ideas in mathematics and similarly disregarded fields are not well-understood is because they are viewed as foreign, and especially in America, there is a long-standing culture of avoiding foreign things. This is very unfortunate, as with even just a little bit of inspiration, mathematics and its beauty are always waiting with welcoming faces. 
<br />
<br />
What does making research progress mean? Type I research does more to expand current knowledge horizontally, as opposed to Type II research which extends itself vertically. New ideas in Type I research are frequent, so often there is a long list of papers and books that is released, with ultimately identical objectives depending on the trend of a certain time period. The nature of Type I research is to travel stagnant with occasional climaxes, where a revolutionary new idea is introduced every once in a while. What follows is a boom of new ideas and diverging papers, but not long after everything turns gray and bleak as people wait for the next climax. In Type I research fields such as biology and chemistry, the main restriction of progress is technology. Our abilities are as good as our own barriers. Type II research approaches things differently. In Mathematics, there are always diverging ideas, and while revolutionary ideas are truly monumental, the realm of possibility is even more endless than one can imagine, and people strive nonstop, nearly incessantly. It’s almost as though I discover a new idea or entirely new field of study every day. Mathematics has no bound on progress. The only thing preventing progress in mathematics is our mental capacity, not the technology that we rely on. I am no humanist, but the fact that I study mathematics is the most human thing that I do. While technology will eventually - and already does - offer the most advanced forms of computation and artificial intelligence, the field of mathematics is what will never become obsolete, because it is simply that impossible to replicate. Type II research is just that: investigating a problem that seems so unreal and so disconnected from reality, pursuing something so inherently human and anthropogenic. 
<br />
<br />
And even with all of this said, Type II research remains a mystery to many, especially to college admissions. While scientific communication of Type I research is crucial to nurturing a developing society, the push for Type II research to be placed in the forefront of modern human progress is not only important, but necessary. Now that I look back, I realise what had disturbed me the most about Type I research projects: the melancholy of the fact that the only thing that can resurface in modern society is something that can be generally understood, and not something that can be appreciated to its fullest.
<br />
<br />
Maybe this is just a naïve interpretation of something that I don’t fully comprehend, but these are some of my thoughts.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An essay that is probably not an essay]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An introduction to this website</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/firstpost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An introduction to this website" /><published>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/firstpost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/firstpost/"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first post on this website. I have created this website to display my work as an amateur mathematician. (It has been largely inspired by a similar website created by my friend Kyle; you can find his website <a href="https://12buntu.github.io/Book-N/">here</a>) Even though I am only a high school student, there are many more opportunities for me to explore my interests in mathematics, and many more opportunities for me to collaborate with friends and professors - or work independently - to produce valuable research.
<br />
<br />
While this space is largely for displaying my formal work, nothing is stopping me from using it to document any of my research journeys, academic interests, or even casual discoveries and playful expositions. All of my work here is done with and sometimes without purpose. The only limitation for whatever interests me is prerequisites, but even that can eventually be transgressed. I guess that means that what I do here is like a cloud… dreamy… drifting, and oh so unpredictable. 
<br />
<br />
Slightly forced metaphors aside, the reason that I have been able to do much of the work displayed here is attributed to a multitude of significant people who have guided me through my expositions and self-discovery. While I cannot name each individual, it is important to acknowledge the origin of this lifelong interest in mathematics. Something so valuable takes an immense amount of passion and belief to awaken, so I would like to thank 王老师 for being the ticket to my future endeavours; the first ray of sun on such a blazing horizon by the sea…</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some words and some nonwords]]></summary></entry></feed>