<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-06-01T15:13:10+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">An introduction to this website</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/firstpost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An introduction to this website" /><published>2023-05-26T23:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-26T23:05:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/firstpost</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/blog/2023/firstpost/"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first post on this website. I have created this website to display my work as an amateur mathematician. (It has been largely inspired by a similar website created by my friend Kyle; you can find his website <a href="https://12buntu.github.io/Book-N/">here</a>) Even though I am only a high school student, there are many more opportunities for me to explore my interests in mathematics, and many more opportunities for me to collaborate with friends and professors - or work independently - to produce valuable research.
<br />
<br />
While this space is largely for displaying my formal work, nothing is stopping me from using it to document any of my research journeys, academic interests, or even casual discoveries and playful expositions. All of my work here is done with and sometimes without purpose. The only limitation for whatever interests me is prerequisites, but even that can eventually be transgressed. I guess that means that what I do here is like a cloud… dreamy… drifting, and oh so unpredictable. 
<br />
<br />
Slightly forced metaphors aside, the reason that I have been able to do much of the work displayed here is attributed to a multitude of significant people who have guided me through my expositions and self-discovery. While I cannot name each individual, it is important to acknowledge the origin of this lifelong interest in mathematics. Something so valuable takes an immense amount of passion and belief to awaken, so I would like to thank 王老师 for being the ticket to my future endeavours; the first ray of sun on such a blazing horizon by the sea…</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some words and some nonwords]]></summary></entry></feed>