<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-07-02T00:28:35+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Journeys VI</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/journeys6/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journeys VI" /><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/journeys6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/journeys6/"><![CDATA[<p>Truthfully, I don’t know what to write. I felt it necessary to write something in these unprecedented times—though I reside in a limbo between knowing what to write and being a giraffe. Sometimes it’s better to not write at all. 
<br />
<br />
(1 July, 2025)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journeys" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[onward]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Quadratic and Cubic Characters of 2</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/quadcub2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Quadratic and Cubic Characters of 2" /><published>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/quadcub2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/quadcub2/"><![CDATA[<p>The submission process is everything but familiar to me. While I did submit to the arXiv, the arXiv is not a peer-reviewed journal, unlike many other mathematical journals. Over the past two months I have been working carefully on a paper that relates closely to the topic in <i> On Finite Fields and Higher Reciprocity </i>, and I was debating whether to submit it to the American Mathematical Monthly (AMM) - a prestigious journal for expository articles that is well-respected in the math community - or another journal such as the Mathematics Magazine (MM). After much thought and revision (as well as some much-needed guidance), I decided that my article was not novel enough to warrant a place in AMM, but that it would perhaps be suitable for MM. So, today (or rather yesterday), I submitted my article to MM. 
<br />
<br />
Here are some thoughts that I have. First, I do not have incredibly high expectations for the publication of this article. While I know that MM is perhaps on the lower end of journals in general (despite featuring incredibly expository work), it still has a lower standard based in originality and novelty. While I think my paper certainly is interesting and would be appropriate to the readership of MM, I am not entirely sure. I guess we’ll see. Second, publication takes a long time. The website for MM indicates that, on average, the first decision regarding an article will be 19 days. Now, this is kind of arbitrary - it can take far longer or far less time. Looking back at previously published articles, it seems that people took anywhere from a few weeks to an entire year to publish. That’s a long time. I guess we’ll see how long this takes!
<br />
<br />
If the paper is rejected from MM, I can still possibly publish in a different undergraduate journal - we’ll see. Either way, I’m going to post this paper on the arXiv at some point. I will update this page if anything happens. 
<br />
<br />
(2 October, 2024)
<br />
<br />
The paper is now informally available on this website. I am still awaiting notice from MM. A pdf (v1) is available <a href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/assets/pdf/matias-quadcub2.pdf">here</a>, and the arXiv preprint is <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.21646">here</a>.
<br />
<br />
(11 October, 2024)
<br />
<br />
This journey has reached an important milestone. It seems that my paper has been “reviewed favorably” by Mathematics Magazine, and after completing minor revisions, it will go on to publication. In this post, I’ll cover a little bit of the timeline of the journey this paper has taken and some of my thoughts.</p>

<p><img src="/quadcryo/assets/img/R_and_R.png" alt="Timeline picture" style="height:100%;width:100%" class="center" /></p>

<p>The above shows a sort of timeline of events in the submission process (I’ll update it later when more stuff happens, but for now, I have until 18 April, 2025 to revise and resubmit for eventual publication). 
<br />
<br />
Here are some initial thoughts. The publication process seems like something really exciting, but in reality, it’s mostly waiting. Just waiting. And a lot of it. This should be pretty clear from the timeline shown as evidenced by the 4 month gap between submission and decision, but it really isn’t put into perspective until you’re in it. I found myself refreshing that page for a while until I eventually gave up - each step in the process felt like an eternal wait, so reaching a point with some more certainty is a great feeling. If I have any more thoughts or any interesting comments about referee comments on my paper, maybe I’ll write more here. For now, it’s just some revisions.
<br />
<br />
(5 March, 2025)
<br />
<br />
Revisions only took about two weeks, and the paper will now be re-examined. Hopefully it takes just a couple weeks. I will post an updated version (v2) to the arXiv before publication, and will update that page accordingly. Thank you to everyone who has contributed to this and helped me throughout the process. As promised, here is an updated timeline.</p>

<p><img src="/quadcryo/assets/img/revisions_submitted.png" alt="Timeline picture" style="height:100%;width:100%" class="center" />
<br />
<br />
(17 March, 2025)
<br />
<br />
The article was returned on 19 June, 2025, with a few brief revisions (typos and punctuation) and one minor remark about an assumption made, as well as a guarantee of acceptance and publication after resubmitted. I made these changes quickly and added a remark to address the assumption, and now I guess I wait until either the paper is sent back out to reviewers (which I would find to be unnecessary because so little has been changed, but it’s not up to me) or accepted by the editor. I think that the two scenarios have a very different timeframe… Either way, here is the timeline updated again. Until later!</p>

<p><img src="/quadcryo/assets/img/R&amp;R submitted again.png" alt="Timeline picture resubmit" style="height:100%;width:100%" class="center" />
<br />
<br />
(20 June, 2025)
<br />
<br />
As of today, 26 June, 2025, this article has been accepted for publication. There was a minor round of revisions from the editor that mostly pointed to punctuation and rephrasing of some sentences which I managed quickly. Mathematics Magazine indicates an average of 45 days from acceptance to online publication, but I don’t know what to expect—I guess it depends on how close 26 June is to any individual 5-times-a-year publication. Below is the final timeline.</p>

<p><img src="/quadcryo/assets/img/article accepted.png" alt="Timeline picture accepted" style="height:100%;width:100%" class="center" /></p>

<p>I suppose now that this project has come to its end, I should talk a bit about what this means to me for eventually pursuing research and doing more like this. At the end of the day, this result is a stepping stone. Yes, I am happy that I completed it, and I am happy that it has been accepted, but there’s a bit of melancholic sadness—it’s like when you’ve achieved something you wanted for a long time and initially feel content, but internally you know that to achieve what you really want, there will be many more seconds, minutes, and hours spent working, doubting, and revising. Those seconds, minutes, and hours seem far away, but they really aren’t—years are now conscious fractions of our lives, and all that we do, whether to advance our career or personal interests, will eventually shape us. 
<br />
<br />
I can’t get ahead of myself. The next decade of my life decides really how I want to diversify my specialty—a bit of an oxymoron, but I think this concept of being specialized yet flexible and interdisciplinary is exactly what the remaining three-quarters of this century demands—and achieve whatever it is I want to achieve. There is work to be done.
<br />
<br />
When the article is published, I will include a link here; I expect the updated article to appear on the arXiv as well.
<br />
<br />
Also I now officially endorse using em-dashes. 
<br />
<br />
(26 June, 2025)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[publishing? what is that?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A word</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/somewords/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A word" /><published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/somewords</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/somewords/"><![CDATA[<p>Today I learned that my teacher, mentor, and friend, Dr. Tamar Avineri, passed away due to cancer. This came as a complete shock to me, and I wanted to dedicate this piece to her and say a few words. 
<br />
<br />
The first class I took with Dr. Avineri was Graph Theory, and I learned a great deal from that experience. It wasn’t until the second semester that I was truly able to work with her after explaining my interest in reciprocity laws - I wrote a paper, and she worked with me to revise it, critiquing my proof-writing and giving her own prose suggestions. During that time, we developed a wonderful relationship. I began to see her as a mentor, as someone who could advise me and someone I could trust. 
<br />
<br />
Going into my senior year, Dr. Avineri was there advising me as I submitted a paper to a journal. Even as she was undergoing cancer treatment - something that I viewed to be a sign of her improving health - she continued to teach and mentor me and others, providing immense support and giving many words of encouragment and wisdom. I remember meeting in her office, over Zoom, and in other places to discuss my work. I remember one day she was working through my paper in her favorite coffee shop while I was in a Zoom meeting with her. Even though it was noisy, she persisted in having the meeting and insisted on advising me.
<br />
<br />
I saw her as a friend. I looked forward to maintaining in contact with her in the future to speak to her about her experiences, to speak about how her creative teaching style and contagious enthusiasm have led me to wherever I will be, to speak to her about my own ambitions and dreams and how she once had them too. I looked forward to Dr. Avineri being in my life even if we were far apart from one another.
<br />
<br />
Dr. Avineri was a good person. I regret that I wasn’t able to say goodbye in the way that I would have hoped. She was kind. She was respectful. She was a wonderful teacher, never giving students the answers but instead guiding them toward it. She represented a fleeting hope for education in this country, always loving and prioritizing her students and defying the ordinary: she saw education as a greater opportunity, and she wanted to impress better education and ideas upon developing people. She even had a great sense of style - even as she was undergoing cancer treatment, she wore a fashionable wrap around her head. She won an award in 2024, and it outlines much of her life story and many accomplishments; it is linked <a href="https://www.ncssm.edu/news/veteran-math-teacher-recognized-with-prestigious-award-from-unc-system">here</a>.
<br />
<br />
There is so much more good to say about Dr. Avineri that it is impossible to contain all of it within this short piece - I wish I would have been able to learn more about her and her past, as well as her future. Dr. Avineri will be missed by many, and I will never forget how she has impacted me. 
<br />
<br />
May she rest in peace.
<br />
<br />
(2 May, 2025)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today I learned that my teacher, mentor, and friend, Dr. Tamar Avineri, passed away due to cancer. This came as a complete shock to me, and I wanted to dedicate this piece to her and say a few words. The first class I took with Dr. Avineri was Graph Theory, and I learned a great deal from that experience. It wasn’t until the second semester that I was truly able to work with her after explaining my interest in reciprocity laws - I wrote a paper, and she worked with me to revise it, critiquing my proof-writing and giving her own prose suggestions. During that time, we developed a wonderful relationship. I began to see her as a mentor, as someone who could advise me and someone I could trust. Going into my senior year, Dr. Avineri was there advising me as I submitted a paper to a journal. Even as she was undergoing cancer treatment - something that I viewed to be a sign of her improving health - she continued to teach and mentor me and others, providing immense support and giving many words of encouragment and wisdom. I remember meeting in her office, over Zoom, and in other places to discuss my work. I remember one day she was working through my paper in her favorite coffee shop while I was in a Zoom meeting with her. Even though it was noisy, she persisted in having the meeting and insisted on advising me. I saw her as a friend. I looked forward to maintaining in contact with her in the future to speak to her about her experiences, to speak about how her creative teaching style and contagious enthusiasm have led me to wherever I will be, to speak to her about my own ambitions and dreams and how she once had them too. I looked forward to Dr. Avineri being in my life even if we were far apart from one another. Dr. Avineri was a good person. I regret that I wasn’t able to say goodbye in the way that I would have hoped. She was kind. She was respectful. She was a wonderful teacher, never giving students the answers but instead guiding them toward it. She represented a fleeting hope for education in this country, always loving and prioritizing her students and defying the ordinary: she saw education as a greater opportunity, and she wanted to impress better education and ideas upon developing people. She even had a great sense of style - even as she was undergoing cancer treatment, she wore a fashionable wrap around her head. She won an award in 2024, and it outlines much of her life story and many accomplishments; it is linked here. There is so much more good to say about Dr. Avineri that it is impossible to contain all of it within this short piece - I wish I would have been able to learn more about her and her past, as well as her future. Dr. Avineri will be missed by many, and I will never forget how she has impacted me. May she rest in peace. (2 May, 2025)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journeys V</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/journeys5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journeys V" /><published>2025-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/journeys5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/journeys5/"><![CDATA[<p>Soon I will become a university student, and this transition from school to university is something rather surreal. With universities accepting and rejecting me, it’s a little discouraging; so often, many people attribute their individual capabilities to their college results, but so much more often that is just not the case. This isn’t a topic that I think is of interest here, but it’s really interesting to consider given the context of academia and government in America in today’s landscape.</p>

<p>It’s rigid, fraudulent, misguided, unqualified, unprofessional, racist, sexist, and demeaning of anyone who doesn’t follow some biased political demand. The state of American education seems to be fragile, with public institutions soon falling to the mercy of state education requirements (often led by vocal people), and private institutions attempting to save face by bowing before the federal government on issues surrounding DEI, affirmative action, etc.. Where do I go? In a country that prides itself on freedom of speech and scientific prowess, practically every new story each day is about how “some person” was taken from their home after exhibiting free speech, or how “this many” scientists lost their jobs because their work mentioned newly “forbidden terms,” a list that includes words such as “gender,” “woman,” or even “Gulf of Mexico,” which is honestly kinda funny.</p>

<p>How do I fit into this new world? Many say that this will all disappear after 4 years, but they’re wrong. This country has already regressed by 20 years, and each day pushes that number higher. I’ll go to a university, but what then? I have no idea what will happen, and seeing as how fragile academia is in this country, it seems that the best thing to do is to leave America as soon as I graduate and pursue post-graduate studies abroad. I can see myself looking back on this website and thinking about how naïve I was to even think about things so far in the future, but maybe I’m right! I’ll never know until it happens.</p>

<p>It’s just a waiting game. It saddens me to think that the world I’ve known might be something entirely different within a decade.
<br />
<br />
(23 March, 2025)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journeys" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[the world, its constituents, and me in today's landscape]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elementary algebra of hyperreals</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/hyperrealnumbers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elementary algebra of hyperreals" /><published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/hyperrealnumbers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2025/hyperrealnumbers/"><![CDATA[<p>A new year has begun, and I still have yet to hear from the Mathematics Magazine. This isn’t the subject of this post though. Over this J-Term, I had the privilege of learning about hyperreal numbers, which extends \(\mathbb{R}\) to the hyperreal numbers by including infinitesimal and infinite numbers. I gave a presentation on this topic that follows the first couple sections of Keisler’s very rigorous (maybe unnecessarily so) treatment of something that seems no more than a recreational creation of Conway, despite its vast history in the development of nonstandard analysis. I didn’t have the opportunity to learn much more, but from what I can see, Keisler’s treatment focuses a lot on words, sentences, and other “grammatical” concepts from model theory that I have yet to learn about. Maybe I’ll take a look at some point in the future. 
<br />
<br />
The presentation in all of its pause-heavy glory is linked <a href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/projectpdf/hyperreals-algebra-slides.pdf">here</a>.
<br />
<br />
(30 January, 2025)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A presentation I gave on the algebra of hyperreal numbers systems, monads, galaxies]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some projects</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/currenttrajectory/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some projects" /><published>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/currenttrajectory</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/currenttrajectory/"><![CDATA[<p>Now that I have finished my paper on higher reciprocity, I have begun thinking about my next project. Even though <i> On Finite Fields and Higher Reciprocity </i> is on the arXiv, I would like to also submit a portion to a journal as mentioned before (the choices are between the College Mathematics Journal and the Mathematics Magazine - I have to choose between them as their targetted audiences are slightly different). I have mentioned this before, but I will likely cover some results leading up to cubic reciprocity in a more expository style: I’m using playful prose in combination with rigorous language to place the law of cubic reciprocity in an entertaining light. 
<br />
<br />
For a long time now I have been interested in Artin reciprocity. Artin reciprocity is the final generalization of reciprocity laws, and understanding even its statement requires substantial knowledge of class field theory, genus theory, algebraic number theory, and more. Cubic reciprocity is a good first step, but so much more is needed to approach Artin reciprocity. I believe a long term mathematics goal would be to read up on more algebra (preferably Dummit and Foote), a lot more algebraic number theory, and finally class field theory. This is usually something taught in an upper-level graduate course, so I don’t expect to study much now. 
<br />
<br />
In the next academic year I will be working on a project concerning knot theory. I’m not exactly sure in which direction this project will go, but I have some particular interest in mosaic knots, and I have a few resources and ideas for open problems to approach. We’ll see where that goes. 
<br />
<br />
Finally, university applications are fast approaching, and I have yet to start. Might as well start soon. 
<br />
<br />
(19 July, 2024)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[as the title indicates]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is mathematics a language?</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/mathasalanguage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is mathematics a language?" /><published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/mathasalanguage</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/mathasalanguage/"><![CDATA[<p>I do a lot of mathematics, so I believe I have some qualifications to answer this question objectively but uniquely and to my own taste. I hear very similar arguments in either situation: if someone believes that mathematics is a language, it is because they believe that it is capable of expressing ideas and facts, it contains symbols that can be read (whether from one language or multiple), and it is able to describe many things; if someone believes that mathematics is not a language, it is because they believe it is incapable of expressing emotion, complex thoughts, and does not possess qualities of art or creativity. Both reasons deserve more questioning. 
<br />
<br />
While both hold some ideas that are true to an extent, I believe that the inability to classify whether mathematics is a language is down to the fact that people do not know enough mathematics: the reasons for either argument are misinformed. I believe that mathematics is distinct from language in the sense that it describes something that is universally true, whether applied in the sense of physical descriptions of phenomena, or pure in the sense that abstraction is the only possible expression of ideas. Language typically develops from a certain form of culture: culture can be defined very loosely, where two friends can have a culture between them and a group of people might find a cultural affinity in collecting watches. In either case, there is almost always a cultural syntax that is commonly understood between members of the culture, but if this language is exposed to members of a different culture, many details might be lost in translation. This occurs on a multitude of levels, because likely a watch-enthusiast would be able to communicate with non-watch-enthusiasts if they are descriptive enough; a culture between two friends might be difficult to explain to members of other cultures, as often the relationship between two individuals is so rooted in experience and familiarity that to understand it would be to <i> be </i> one of the said friends. 
<br />
<br />
Mathematics, however, is different. Yes, while mathematics does have a culture in the sense that educational institutions often contort the meaning of who <i> does </i> mathematics - whether it is white men at Oxford University in the 19th century who twiddle their thumbs and “think about equations”, or young people pushing new ideas and theories that no one has heard of or is willing to hear about - the ambiguity of mathematical culture is so confusing that it is impossible to differentiate “this mathematics” from “that mathematics”. Under every single misconception and opinion regarding mathematics in any environment is a truth: every single well-established fact is true no matter what cultural syntax is used to express it. Some people believe pure mathematics is unimportant, but even if that may be true, it exists beyond the purpose of objective mathematical syntax: it just doesn’t matter. 
<br />
<br />
I believe the first point at which you can truly consider what mathematics is is when you encounter proof. Many a mathematician will know how variable the way in which a result can be proven truly is, and I can say that I have written proofs in many different ways. Considerations of “elegance” and “non-elegance” are subjective, but they absolutely play a crucial role in determining whether something is beautiful or not. There are even many types of syntax with which a proof can be described, whether it is strictly using logic or using analogy. In either case, whether a proof uses a particular system of logic or field-related syntax, what it fundamentally describes is true no matter what. 
<br />
<br />
This brings me to the following. Does it even mean anything to question whether mathematics is a language? Mathematics is so different from any human or non-human language because it simply does not possess a universal cultural syntax. Rather, it is an amalgamation of the vocabulary from every single possible culture and it exists beyond self and other. Whether it is a language has no meaning: the people or things who - or that - do mathematics have their own interpretation of what mathematics is and how it can be expressed. Humanity is not developed enough to understand how different mathematics looks in different cultural syntaxes, but a good example that would seem distant for many anyway would be something like the difference between two different fields: say category theory and number theory. While these certainly have many connections (I will not describe them because I am not familiar enough of either field), on the surface level, one would never think that number theory - something that can be described fairly easily (it’s definitely not easy, but the “big picture” ideas are more easily accessible) - is related to the often archaic seeming diagrams and ideas of category theory. Yet it is eye-opening to realize how much number theory really does fit in the framework of category theory: structures in number theory have vivid relationships with other structures in category theory. 
<br />
<br />
Ultimately, I believe that mathematics deserves to be separate from language; by analogy, history is often attributed to the humanities, but more often than not it behaves more like a social science, where arguments are shaped and deduced rather than discovered. Mathematics is just that in a different way: a study that is neither a language nor a science, but something else entirely. 
<br />
<br />
(1 July, 2024)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="literature" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some thoughts about whether mathematics should or should not be a language]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journeys IV</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/journeys4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journeys IV" /><published>2024-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/journeys4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/journeys4/"><![CDATA[<p>We will always relearn old facts. Addition and multiplication appear so frequently and so fundamentally that you just can’t avoid them. They chase you around in circles, and much of mathematics is like that. Like addition and multiplication, some topics in mathematics are so fundamental that at any stage of progression or expertise, you will encounter the same things over and over again. It’s well known that repetition can further ingrain certain concepts in your head, but sometimes doing it too much can cause you to implode: if you’ve seen something so many times and understand a concept so well, at what point will seeing it one more time cause you to forget everything I know?</p>

<p>I don’t know the answer to that question. It was meant to be rhetorical, because maybe it doesn’t have an answer at all, or it is specific to each individual mathematician. This leads me to a conversation about the American education system: it doesn’t work. An education system must equally combine cognitive capability with general aptitude with certain precision to produce the best students and inspire self-growth and independent thinking. China has a wonderful education system, in that children are burnt out by middle school and commit suicide with the same frequency with which the earth orbits the sun. America has a wonderful education system, in that it treats everyone equally with very little consideration for differences in capability, instead insisting that everyone is “very good”, neglecting those who suffer and those who excel. Not to mention the frequent school shootings, but that’s a discussion for another time. Both are examples of extremes.</p>

<p>China has it’s own educational problems, but ultimately it produces intelligent, capable, individuals who will without doubt go on to achieve great things. America, perhaps not so much. Especially in regard to mathematics education, educators often reiterate to their most advanced students how great they are. While it can be a good motivator, sometimes a student can be most benefitted when told the truth. The truth is that not everyone is brilliant, and conversely, not everyone is stupid. I believe that every mathematics student should always be humbled by what they encounter. I say this from experience, as I find that I learn the most about both myself and my potential when I am made aware of my lack of knowledge.</p>

<p>While trivialities and repetition are necessary, it is through struggling and not being told how “great” you are that you really push yourself. You should always strive to be better. However, you should also know your own bounds. An example is the field of topology. The value of topology is in its rigour, but to truly digest that rigour, you mustn’t go about it like reading a children’s book and looking at pictures like topology is some mystical field. I admit that right now, I don’t have the background to learn topology. I don’t deserve to learn topology because I would only do the field and myself a disservice: I know nothing of what topology really should be, and to treat it exactly like a picture book would make me hate the subject. Regardless of what anyone says, this is a fact. You must know what you can and cannot do.</p>

<p>So, to change my tone to one of more optimism, maybe some repetition can be beneficial. I have always found helping others with mathematics to be a wonderful opportunity to test your own depth of knowledge, so perhaps when you are familiar with something you can be of assistance to others. Maybe there is truly a teacher in me after all.</p>

<p>It is difficult to quantify what mathematical growth truly means. Personally, mathematical growth is dictated by my ability to read proofs, to understand difficult concepts, and to approach a field with enough confidence and experience to be leisurely curious. In other words, mathematical maturity. However, “growth” suggests that I’m gaining something, that I’m not only applying what I’m knowing but being surprised by little things and large things that I’ve never encountered before that develop my mathematical maturity. While learning old mathematics may solidify my mathematical maturity, it rarely gives me new insights into something I already know (unless it is something I know little about). Perhaps I should find positive in relearning old mathematics and seek out things that I never would have considered? Perhaps I should enter new dialogues on adjacent topics to gain enrichment in another form? I don’t really know. We’ll see.
<br />
<br />
(30 June, 2024)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="journeys" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do I reconcile relearning old mathematics with my mathematical growth?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cubic and Biquadratic reciprocity FINAL VERSION</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/cubicbiquadratic(update)/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cubic and Biquadratic reciprocity FINAL VERSION" /><published>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/cubicbiquadratic(update)</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/cubicbiquadratic(update)/"><![CDATA[<p>UPDATE (7 July, 2024): The paper is now on this site as well as on the arXiv. For the version on this website, check <a href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/papers/">here</a>. For the version on the arXiv, check <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.03559">here</a>.
<br />
<br />
Hello! It has been a while since I have last posted, but here I am now! A few months ago (January or so) I started working on a paper related to the study of Galois fields (finite fields) and higher reciprocity. Since then I have written nearly 45 pages, and it is quite nearly complete. Over these few months, I have furthered my mathematical maturity, taken advice and learned a lot from both peers and professors, and experienced a few revelations here and there in relation to some topics or proofs. I also created a poster and gave a sort of informal presentation on the paper! Writing is hard, and when you’re busy it’s difficult to make significant progress. I think I initially said that I would complete this by the end of January; then the end of March; then May; and now look, it’s already June. I wouldn’t say this is procrastination at all - rather a combination of business and a quest for greater mathematical maturity. 
<br />
<br />
Even while this paper is not fully complete, I will provide the abstract for any who are interested in reading about what is covered in the paper. 
<br />
<br />
<i> Abstract </i><br />
<br />
Cubic and biquadratic reciprocity have long since been referred to as ``the forgotten reciprocity laws”, largely since they provide special conditions that are widely considered to be unnecessary in the study of number theory. However, this paper aims to approach reciprocity with ample detail to motivate its existence. In this exposition of finite fields and higher reciprocity, we will begin by introducing concepts in abstract algebra and elementary number theory. This will motivate our approach toward understanding the structure and then existence of finite fields, especially with a focus on understanding the multiplicative group \(\mathbb{F}^{*}\). While surveying finite fields we will provide another proof of quadratic reciprocity. We will proceed to investigate properties of the general multiplicative character, covering the concept of a general Gauss sum as well as basic notions of the Jacobi sum. From there we will begin laying the foundations for the cubic reciprocity law, beginning with a classification of the primes and units of the Eisenstein integers, denoted \(\mathbb{Z}[\omega]\), and further investigations into the residue class ring \(\mathbb{Z}[\omega]/\pi\mathbb{Z}[\omega]\) for \(\pi\) prime, which is predominantly the world in which cubic reciprocity lies.</p>

<p>We will then use multiplicative characters to define the cubic residue character and state cubic reciprocity in its entirety. Following this, we provide a proof of the cubic reciprocity law as well as its supplementary theorems using cubic Gauss sums. We will finish the section on cubic reciprocity with a brief survey of the cubic residue character of the even prime \(2\) and state a significant result due to Gauss that summarizes the conditions for \(2\) to be a cubic residue.</p>

<p>We conclude with the statement of biquadratic reciprocity and provide a brief discussion on how it relates to cubic reciprocity in both its proof and usage of the analogy between the Eisenstein integers, \(\mathbb{Z}[\omega]\), and the Gaussian integers, \(\mathbb{Z}[i]\). 
<br />
<br />
When the completed paper appears, I will reference it here. I will likely put it on the arXiv. (it is now there at the top of this page)
<br />
<br />
UPDATE (25 June, 2024): I have decided that I will submit a section of this paper to either the <i> Mathematics Magazine </i> or the <i> College Mathematics Journal </i>. To prepare for submission I will need to edit one particular section to be in a more expository form with plenty of examples, and I might even need to shorten it since it is currently 15 pages, and the alleged limit for either magazine is approximately 14 pages. (25 June, 2024)
<br />
<br />
(Updated 7 July, 2024)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Abstract for a new finished paper]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Surreal numbers omnific integers</title><link href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/surrealnumbers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surreal numbers omnific integers" /><published>2024-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/surrealnumbers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/memoirs/2024/surrealnumbers/"><![CDATA[<p>I had the pleasure of spending a couple weeks learning the basics of the surreal numbers sytem, from the Peano axioms to the basic construction of surreals. At the end of this short exploration, I looked into the world of omnific integers, which generalise the concept of integers to the surreal numbers. For instance, while the integers may contain numbers such as 5, 10, or 1000, the omnific integers include numbers such as \(\omega\), which is the supposed smallest infinite number. Omnific integers allow you to do arithmetic with infinitely large numbers, and for this reason it can be extended to consider many problems in number theory as well. One aspect that I investigated very shallowly was Pell’s equation and how its solution may differ if all integers are instead omnific. 
<br />
<br />
During this short exploration, I made use of Knuth’s <i> Surreal Numbers </i>, which is a sort of novelette that explores the construction and discovery of surreal numbers through the lens of two individuals on a desolate island. It’s perhaps not the most rigorous “math text”, but it certainly has value and can be read like a storybook. I also looked into Conway’s (RIP) <i> On Numbers and Games </i>, which studies surreal numbers in its numerous aspects, from algebra to analysis to number theory, and eventually to the reason for its initial creation: games. It certainly is a rigorous text, but it is very self-contained, and if I had more time I would have been able to explore its nuances in much more detail than I have. At the end of my exploration, I gave a very brief presentation on omnific integers, and here are the <a href="https://quadcryo.github.io/quadcryo/projectpdf/omnific_slides.pdf">slides</a>.
<br />
<br />
(13 January, 2024)
<br />
<br />
In looking over some old stuff, I realized that I keep on referencing and returning to the idea of surreal numbers, either as a joke or as sort of false nostalgia that I have no right to feel. I realize now that I forgot to share one really cool video on the topic, so here it is: <a href="https://youtu.be/ZYj4NkeGPdM?si=Nd1gx6qzyD9VkASn">HACKENBUSH: a window to a new world of math</a>. Enjoy!
<br />
<br />
(17 April, 2025)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="mathematics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fun exploration into game theory and a new number system]]></summary></entry></feed>